썸 오브 올 피어스 (The Sum of All Fears, 2002)
1973년, 이집트와 시리아는
이스라엘을 기습 침공했다
ln 1973, Egypt and Syria launched
a surprise attack against lsrael.
발발 이틀 째, 이스라엘 지상군은
패전을 눈 앞에 두고 있었고
By Day Two, lsraeli ground forces
appeared on the verge of defeat.
자국 군이 괴멸할 경우를
대비한 이스라엘 측은
ln the event that their ground forces
were overrun,
한 대의 A-4기에
초계 임무를 맡겼다
an lsraeli A-4 jet
took off on patrol. . .
하나의 핵 폭탄과 함께...
. . .with one nuclear bomb.
그로부터 29년 후
미국 버지니아주 웨더 산
- Sure it's the Russians?
- 100%, sir.
- 러시아가 틀림 없소?
- 확실합니다
잠수함에서 메가톤급 미사일들이
발사됐고 공격 개시 상태입니다
Submarine launched 12 to 15 megatons.
They went to strike status.
루즈벨트 호가 크루즈 미사일
6기를 격추시켰지만
The Roosevelt's splashed
six incoming Cruise missiles.
수적으로 열세인 베를린 여단으론
서쪽으로의 진격을 막지 못합니다
The Russians are moving west.
Our Berlin brigade are outnumbered.
중부의 알예스크에서도
뭔가가 발사됐습니다
Sir, we've got a launch from Alyesk,
Central Russia.
거기엔 뭐가 있나?
What the hell is in Alyesk?
대륙간 탄도미사일 SS-18인데
뉴욕과 이곳 워싱턴이 목표죠
SS-18 ICBMs. Probable targets -
New York, Washington, here.
- 여긴 얼마나 안전하지?
- 명중만 안 하면 됩니다
- How good is this ceiling?
- Anything but a direct hit.
위성도 미사일들을 포착했습니다
도달 시간은 25분 후입니다
Satellites confirm birds in the air,
first impact estimated 25 minutes.
- 정확한 건가?
- 정확합니다
- Is that accurate?
- It's accurate.
- 데프콘-1을 내려야 합니다
- 조르킨 대통령 연결하게
- I advise we go to DEFCON-1.
- Get President Zorkin on the hotline.
행방이 불명합니다
쿠데타가 일어나서
Zorkin is missing. We have reports
of a coup in Moscow.
불가코프 장군이
집권한 상태입니다
General Bulgakov
is calling the shots now.
불가코프는 또 누군가?
Who the hell is Bulgakov?
체첸에서의 핵 사용을 주장했었죠
The asshole who wanted
to use nukes in Chechnya.
어서 데프콘-1을 내리시죠
Sir, DEFCON-1. We're out of time.
하게
Do it.
대통령 각하
Mr. President.
명령을 내린 후 1분 간의
발사 준비 시간이 소요됩니다
It'll take a minute for the launch
to process after you give the order.
수행 전에
명령 확인 절차가 필요합니다
Before the order can be taken,
an ID check must be performed.
위에서 다섯 번째 번호네
My ID number is fifth from the top.
- 각하, 영부인 전화입니다
- 고맙네
- Sir, it's your wife on 2104.
- Thank you.
- 네
- 2인 승인 규칙에 따라...
- Yeah.
- The order must be confirmed
- 명령 확인이 이루어집니다
- 젠장
- By someone on the approved list.
- Shit.
진 리벨, 국가안보보좌관...
Gene Revell,
National Security Advisor.
검정 넥타이로? 그래, 곧 가지
Is it black tie? OK. I'm on my way.
미안하지만...
Can we...
다음에 끝내면 어떻겠나?
finish this up some other time?
안되죠
No.
이 훈련도 업데이트가
필요하다네, 빌리
We've got to update these fire drills,
Billy.
진짜로 일이 발생하면
난 안 들어갈 거네
If the shit ever hits the fan,
I'm not going underground.
그대로 무덤이 될 테니까
It's a goddamn tomb down there.
이젠 러시아 말고 다른 나라를
가상의 적으로 삼아야 됩니다
We have to choose someone else to
face off against besides the Russians.
그런가? 2만7천기의 핵무기를
보유한 나라가 또 있나 보군
Really? Let's see. Who else has
27,000 nukes for us to worry about?
한 개를 가진 나라가 위험하죠
It's the guy with one I'm worried about.
러시아에 사찰단을 보내서
I have to send some folks to Russia,
아마자스에 있는 핵무기
해체 시설을 조사해야겠네
inspect their nuclear decommissioning
facility at Armazas.
- 아자마스죠
- 어쨌거나
- Arzamas.
- Yeah, whatever.
- 자네 쪽에서 가줘야겠어
- 제가 가죠
- Someone from your staff should go.
- I'll go.
- 빌리, 다른 사람 보내
- 가고 싶습니다
- Billy, send staff.
- I want to go.
좋네
OK.
조르킨을 과소평가 말게, 경제와
범죄, 체첸을 다루는 솜씨가...
Don't underestimate Zorkin. Between
his economy, crime, Chechnya...
- 간이 안 좋죠
- 그렇기야 하지, 현 건강 상태는?
- His liver.
- What's left of it. How is he?
오늘 기자 회견을 한다니까
앉을 순 있는 모양입니다
He's scheduled a press conference
for today, so we know he can sit up.
버지니아주 랭글리, CIA 본부
체첸은 러시아의 영토요
Chechnya is part of Russia.
(SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
(TRANSLATES) Only criminals
and the West wish it to be separate.
범죄자들과 서방의 동조자들만이
분리 독립을 주장하고 있소
대통령 각하
이쪽으로 오시겠습니까?
Mr. President, if you will kindly
come back...
다들 같은 생각이지?
Do you guys see what I see?
- 재킷 말야?
- 전엔 단추를 다 채웠거든
- His jacket?
- He used to be able to button it up.
살이 쪘어
He's getting fat.
그 기분 알지, 저걸 봐
- I know how he feels. Look at that.
- Maybe it's not the same jacket.
같은 옷이 아닐 걸
It has shiny sleeves. He wore it
last time he got out of hospital.
아냐, 소매가 반들거려
퇴원할 때 입었던 거야
- He's off the diet.
- And off the wagon. He slurred...
- 다이어트를 중지했어
- 술도 마시고, 발음도 불분명해...
(RUSSIAN)
Must be why Cherlinski's there -
to keep him off the sauce.
첼린스키가 옆에 붙은 것도
술을 못 마시게 하려는 거야
Where's Cherlinski?
첼린스키가 어디 있어?
저 여자 옆... 누구더라?
갈색 머리 여자 말야
Next to... What's her name?
The chick with the brown hair.
- 엘레나 리쉬코프
- 첼린스키가 아냐
- Elena Rishkov.
- That is not Cherlinski.
땡! 아니긴, 첼린스키 맞아
Bzz! Busted. It's Cherlinski.
첼피츠키로 본 모양인데
아니올시다
You're thinking Cherpitski. It ain't him.
- 분명 첼린스키 맞아
- 아니래도, 정말이야
- I know. It's Cherlinski.
- No, it's not. Trust me.
엘레나 리쉬코프 옆에 있잖아?
제네바 정상회담 때 같이 잤어
He's next to Elena Rishkov. He was
banging her at the Geneva summit.
제네바는 첼린스키가 아니라
첼피츠키였어
Cherlinski was not at Geneva.
Cherpitski was.
첼피츠키가 저 여자와 잤다고?
Cherpitski was banging Elena Rishkov?
왜 조르킨의 몸무게 얘기하다
섹스 얘기로 새지? 정말 못 말려
I just said Zorkin's putting on weight.
Why reduce it to sex? It's disgusting.
맞아, 기록해 둬, 체중이 느는 건
I agree. Write it up.
If he is putting on weight,
건강상의 이상 징후니까
오후 브리핑 때 넣어
that might have health consequences,
so get it in the afternoon brief.
누가 여자랑 잤는지도 알아내
좋은 정보야
Oh, and somebody find out who is
banging Elena Rishkov. This is good.
오스트리아 비엔나
서방에 도움을 청하는
체첸을 어떻게 봐야 할까요?
What shall we make of Chechnya
asking the West for protection?
어여쁜 처녀가 욕정을 못 이기는
곰의 손아귀에서 벗어나
She is like a beautiful virgin, escaping
the clutches of a lecherous bear,
순결을 지키려고
클린턴에게 달려가는 꼴이죠
and running to Bill Clinton
to save her maidenhood.
어느 시인이 이랬다죠
'진흙탕을 피하다 늪을 만나리'
A poet once wrote, "Meet the new
boss, same as the old boss."
21세기를 맞은 우리 유럽의
상황에 딱 맞는 말입니다
He could have been writing of us,
of Europe in the 21st century.
미국과 러시아는 50년 간
Over 50 years of America and Russia
유럽에 영향력을 행사해 왔습니다
imposing their will
on the European community,
동쪽과 서쪽에서 말이죠
East and West,
우릴 어린애 취급을 하면서도
and we're still treated like children...
장난감이나 초콜릿은
주지도 않습니다
but without the toys
or the goodnight chocolates.
우린 매일 잃고 있습니다
Each day we lose a little more
우리의 미래를 결정할
고유의 자결권을 말입니다
of our separate sovereign ability
to determine our own futures
하루하루 세계는 그 끔찍한
시간을 향해 다가가고 있습니다
and each day the world comes just a
little bit closer to that terrible moment
나비의 날개 짓이
허리케인을 불러올 겁니다
when the beating of a butterfly's wings
unleashes a hurricane...
그 땐 신도 어쩔 수 없죠
...God himself cannot stop.
(DIGGING)
(SPADE HITS METAL)
대체 뭐야?
(ARABIC) What is it?
보고도 몰라요?
Are you blind?
폭탄이잖아요
It's a bomb.
신관은 어디야?
Where's the fuse?
따뜻해요
It's warm.
나도 그래, 시간 없으니까 서둘러
So am I. Come on.
I don't have all night.
불발탄인가 봐요
It's a dud.
어서 트럭에 실어
Let's get it on the truck.
이런 걸 누가 사요?
But how can we sell it now?
고철도 살 사람은 있게 마련이야
There's always someone
who'll buy this crap.
내 건강이 어떻다고
그렇게 난리를 피워
(IN RUSSIAN) I cannot stand
all these questions about my health.
이렇게 튼튼한데 보고도 모르나
I am to be described as
"robust" and "healthy".
(RUSSIAN)
(SHOUTS ORDER)
(PAGER BUZZES)
당신 거야, 내 거야?
Is that yours or mine?
당신 거겠지, 내 건 전시용이거든
It must be yours. Mine's just for show.
(TURNS IT OFF)
병원이 아냐
It's not the hospital.
- 안녕
- 아직 안 갔네
- Hi.
- You're still here.
말은 바로 해야지
당신이 안 간 거야
Well, I think to be accurate,
it's actually you who's still here.
그래, 맞아
Oh, right.
나쁘다는 건 아냐
Not that I'm complaining.
잭
...
Jack...
좀 놀랄지도 모르겠지만...
I know this is new and all, but...
지금 안 말하면 미칠 것만 같아
I have something to say or I'll explode.
겁 먹지 않음 좋겠어
I don't want you to be scared.
뭔데?
What?
당신은 사랑에 빠졌어
You're in love with me.
난 이 분야 전문가야
증상을 잘 알아
Jack, I'm a medical professional.
I can read the symptoms.
나랑 사랑에 빠진 거야
You're definitely in love with me.
그래서 겁나?
And that scares you?
조금도 겁 안나
Not even a little.
당신이 겁 날 것 같은데?
But I think it scares you.
나도 조금도 겁 안나
No, not even a little.
분명히 해두지만
당신이 먼저 말했어
And for the record,
you're the one who brought it up.
(PAGER BUZZES)
그냥 둬
Forget it.
- 한 번 볼 게
- 지치면 멈추겠지
- I'm gonna get it.
- No way. It'll stop.
누군지 모르겠는 걸
I don't know who this is.
- 하던 일 계속해
- 하필 이런 때
- Go about your business.
- The timing sucks.
이해할 테니까 계속 일 봐
Do what you have to do.
네, 멀러인데요
Yes, this is Dr. Muller.
멀러요, 호출했죠?
Muller. You paged me.
여보세요
Hello. Stop!
Yes, this is Jack Ryan.
그만, 잭 라이언 맞아요
맙소사
Jesus.
네, 30분 내로 가죠
OK. I'll be there in half an hour.
가야겠어, 직장에 비상이 걸렸어
I gotta go. I have
an emergency at work.
정말 미안해
I have to go. I'm sorry.
캐시, 오늘 저녁 어때?
Cathy, how about dinner tonight?
좋아
Yeah.
- 내일 저녁은?
- 오늘 좋다고 했어
- How about tomorrow night?
- Jack, I said yes to tonight.
알아
I know.
대체 역사학자에게 무슨 비상이래?
What kind of emergency
does a historian have?
표준시로 04시 20분 사망, 8시간
30분 후 새 대통령이 취임했어
He died at 0420 Zulu. 8¹/² hours
later, they swore in a new president.
- 누가 취임했는데요?
- 알렉산더 네메로프
- Who is he?
- Alexander Nemerov.
설마? 1년 전
분석 보고서를 올린 자예요
You're kidding. I wrote a paper
about him a year ago.
- 내가 차기 집권자로 찍었다고요
- 그래, 알아
- I said he could be the next guy.
- I know.
- 거들떠보지 않더니
- 지금은 읽느라 바빠
- Nobody read it.
- They're reading it now.
- 누가?
- 캐봇 국장
- Who?
- Cabot.
1년 넘게 일했지만
내 얼굴도 모를 걸
I've been here 14 months.
He doesn't know...
- 자네가 라이언인가?
- 그렇습니다
- Are you Ryan?
- Yes, sir.
'하버드의 공부벌레들' 찍나?
What is this? "The Paper Chase"?
- 급하게...
- 가지, 늦었네
- Sir, my...
- Come on, we're late.
근무하던 곳과는
성격이 다르니까 잘 듣게
You're about to breathe air
that's way over your pay grade.
요청이 있을 때만 말하고
확실한 내용만 얘기하게
You'll be asked for advice. Be sure
you know what you're talking about.
모른다고 해도 탓하지 않네
Don't be afraid to say you don't know.
무엇보다 신중하게 말해
정책에 반영되니까
Choose your words carefully.
They could become policy.
자네, 웃옷 좀 벗게
Hey, you. Give me your coat.
어서, 돌려주겠네
Come on, you'll get it back.
넥타이도
Tie.
가는 곳이 정보 위원회인가요?
So, Intelligence Committee?
케이블 방송으로 본 적이 있죠
참석한 적은 없지만요
I've watched these on C-SPAN.
Never actually been to one.
이런 자리는 공개된 적이 없네
You've never watched
one of these on C-SPAN.
가장 민감한 정보는 그곳 내부의
'출처'에 의존합니다
Our most important assessment comes
from a source inside the Kremlin.
그에 따르면 네메로프는
군부를 등에 업지 않았습니다
In his opinion, Nemerov does not owe
his ascension to the military.
누구나생각이 있는 법이고
Everyone has opinions, Mr. Cabot.
난 그걸 존중하오
I respect that.
오늘 아침 아내가 날 못생긴
대머리 늙은이라고 했소
This morning, my wife woke up
and said I was old, bald and ugly.
질문하신 건가요, 위원장님?
Is that a question, Mr. Chairman?
난 겉 모습이 다는
아니라고 대답했소
I told her
appearances aren't everything.
- 동의하시오?
- 물론입니다
- Would you agree?
- I certainly would.
그럼, 그 네즈메로즈란 자가...
이름이 맞소?
Now, this new fellow, Nezmeroz.
Is that his name?
네메로프입니다
Nemerov, sir.
당신의 정보와는 달리
우린 강경론자라고 알고 있소
Despite what your source says,
we hear that Nezmeroz is a hardliner.
강경론자 맞소?
Is he a hardliner?
아닙니다
(No.)
좀더 시간을 두고 봐야 합니다
It's too soon to make that assessment.
CNN에 따르면
According to CNN,
네즈메로즈가 신 러시아 제국의
건설을 천명했다고 하는데
your Mr. Nezmeroz is making promises
to rebuild the Russian empire.
아주 경솔한 발언 같소이다
That sounds pretty rash
from where I sit.
내가 체첸에 산다면
더욱 염려될 일이오
If I were sitting in Chechnya,
I'd be even more worried.
강경파를 달래려는
발언이었을 뿐인데요
(Nemerov only said that
to get the hardliners off his back.
그냥 두면 그곳은
안정을 찾을 겁니다
(If we leave him alone,
Russia will stabilise.)
조언을 하라는 게
직접 말하란 뜻은 아니었네
When I asked for your advice, I didn't
mean that you should actually speak.
캐봇 국장?
Mr. Cabot?
네메로프에 정통한
러시아 내의 우리 정보원들이
Some of our assets in the Russian
government who know Mr. Nemerov
아직 보고를 안 한 상태입니다
have not reported in.
판단하기엔 이르니
수 일 더 정보가 수집되면
I'd like to take a couple of days
to gather more information
확답을 드릴까 합니다
before characterising him,
하지만 겉 모습만으로
판단하는 건 위험합니다
but I do maintain my opinion
that appearances can be deceiving.
내가 틀렸다는 거요?
You're saying I'm wrong?
그렇습니다, 위원장님
Absolutely, Mr. Chairman.
못생기지 않으셨거든요
I don't think you're ugly.
- 주제 넘게 굴어 죄송합니다
- 그들은 놀라는 걸 싫어하네
- I was out of line. I apologise.
- Senators don't like to be surprised.
먼저 어떤 말을 할지 암시를 준 뒤
받아들일 시간을 주고
I hint at what I'm gonna tell them, then
I give them a while to get used to it.
본론을 꺼내야지
Then I tell them.
- 알겠습니다
- 그래
- I understand.
- Good.
하지만 강경론자는 아닙니다
But I'm right about Nemerov.
자네 애인이 그런 고집 좋아하나?
Your girlfriend like
this stubborn streak in you?
네?
What?
캐시 멀러, 2년차 외과 레지던트
Cathy Muller,
second year surgical resident,
볼티모어 메모리얼 병원
Baltimore Memorial Hospital.
이런 게 CIA 아닌가?
Welcome to the CIA, sport.
정보에 오차가 있네요
애인이 아닙니다, 아직은요
Your intelligence is a little flawed.
I wouldn't call her my girlfriend... yet.
- 그럼 뭐라고 부르나?
- '대단해, 끝내줘'요
- What exactly would you call her?
- Great. Amazing.
지속적인 관계를 두려워하죠
She's afraid to commit.
지속적인 관계를 두려워해
He's terrified of commitment.
세 번 데이트 하고 지레 겁 먹어?
정말 뉴스 감이다
Afraid of commitment after three dates?
Alert the media.
- 나도 알아
- 무슨 일 하는데?
- I know, I know.
- So what does he do?
등을 다쳐 해병대에서 전역했어
He was in the Marines
before he hurt his back.
- 지금은 역사학자야
- 따분하겠다
- Now he's a historian.
- Yawn.
안 그래, 강 건너
'싱크 탱크'에서 일한대
No. He works for a think tank
across the river.
따분 곱빼기다
Double yawn.
좋아, 리타, 저녁에 보고도
그런 소리가 나오나 보자
All right, Rita. Let's see what you have
to say after we meet him tonight.
그럼...
He's...
귀여워?
...cute?
- 난 손가락이 너무 굵어
- 캐시! 10점 만점에 몇 점?
- I have fat fingers.
- Cathy! Cute scale, one to ten.
모르겠어, 글쎄...
Oh, God. I don't know.
12점?
Twelve.
어디서 찾았는지 물어보게
Ask them where they found this.
(SPEAKS ARABIC)
(RESPONDS IN ARABIC)
골란의 평원이랍니다
In the field, in the Golan.
1973년에 치열한 전투가
벌어진 곳인데 직접 봤을까?
There was a lot of fighting there
in 1973. Did they witness it?
(ARABIC)
This one says he lost his son.
그 때 아들을 잃었답니다
당시 격추된 비행기가
없었는지 물어보게
Does he remember,
was there a plane shot down?
(ARABIC)
네, 이스라엘 제트기였답니다
Yes, an Israeli jet, destroyed.
This is worthless.
이건 고철이네
(TRANSLATES)
But tell him I will give him $400...
because of his son.
하지만 4백 달러 쳐주지
잃은 아들을 위해서
(TRANSLATES INTO ARABIC)
Thank... thank you.
고마... 고맙습니다
Thank you.
고맙습니다
시리아 다마스커스
Not something you'd find lying around.
How did you come by it?
어디서 구하신 거죠?
(WOMAN) I found her in the attic of
an old mansion house in Glasgow.
글래스고에 있는 한 오랜 저택의
지하실에서 찾아낸 거예요
덕분에 시가로 1천 파운드 상당의
물건을 소유하게 되신 겁니다
Your trip to the attic has got you
a piece worth now about £ 1,000.
Even in this condition. And had she
been in better condition, even more.
지금보다 상태가 더 양호했다면
더 높은 가치를 지녔을 텐데요
A jolly nice find.
횡재하신 겁니다
How did this beautiful lady
end up with a broken nose?
원하는 걸 찾았음
가격은 미화 5천만 불
(WOMAN) I can't tell you.
- This happened before I found her.
- You found her?
1973년도 이스라엘제
마크 12형 분열 폭탄
Yes. She was very, very dirty
and she was in a pile of rubble.
In fact, what I thought I'd found
was a garden ornament.
정원 장식품이겠거니
그렇게 생각했죠
여보세요, 캐시?
Hello, Cathy?
Hi. I'm glad you called. I'm running late.
Can you come a half an hour later?
마침 잘 했어, 좀 늦을 것
같으니까 30분 늦게 와
I can't make it. I'm really sorry.
못 갈 것 같아, 정말 미안해
- It's a last-minute work thing.
- What's that noise?
- 막판에 일이 터져서
- 무슨 소리가 나네?
I'm calling from a plane.
비행기 안이거든
- This just came up. I tried to call you.
- Where are you going?
- 아까 병원으로 전화하려 했어
- 어디 가는데?
- I can't tell you that.
- Jack.
- 그건 말 못해
- 잭
You can't tell me?
말 못한다고?
잭
Jack.
- Hold on. Yes, sir?
- What are you doing?
- 잠깐, 네?
- 뭐 하는 건가?
I had a date tonight, so I had to cancel.
오늘 데이트를 취소하는 건데요
Don't be stupid. Tell her where you're
going. Tell her who you work for.
왜 숨기나? 다 말해주게
뭘 하는 곳인지도 다
She'll be impressed.
우러러 볼 걸세
OK. I work for the CIA.
좋아, 난 CIA에서 일해
The director asked me to go with him to
Russia to do a nuclear arms inspection.
국장님하고 핵무기 사찰을 위해
러시아에 가는 중이야
- Hello?
- That is so lame.
- 듣고 있어?
- 너무 어설퍼
정말이야, 핵무기 해체를
사찰하러 가는 거라니까
I swear. We get to inspect to make sure
they're decommissioning their arsenal.
Hello?
여보세요?
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
네, 큰 도움이 됐네요
Zdravstvuyte, William Cabot.
안녕하시오, 윌리엄 캐봇 국장
President Nemerov.
네메로프 대통령님
Pleasure, sir.
영광입니다
May I present Mrs. Lathrop.
이쪽은 래스롭입니다
Mr. President.
안녕하십니까
- General Rand.
- Mr. President.
- 랜드 장군
- 안녕하십니까
- Dr. Ryan.
- Mr. President.
- 라이언 박사
- 안녕하십니까
(NEMEROV SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN)
You must be the Dr. Ryan who's done
such interesting research on me.
나에 대해 흥미로운 연구를 했던
장본인이시군요
(RUSSIAN)
You should not be surprised.
We know quite a bit.
놀랄 것 까지야...
알만큼은 알고 있소
(RUSSIAN)
We know how wrong your report was
that I had many girlfriends in college.
내가 대학 시절에 많은 여자를
사귀었다고 한 부분은 틀렸지만
(RUSSIAN)
I met my wife in my third year and have
not looked at another woman since.
3학년 때 지금의 아내를 만난 뒤론
한 눈을 판 적이 없소
I was referring to
the first two years... sir.
1, 2학년 때를
말했던 겁니다, 각하
(IN RUSSIAN) Where you received
highest honours in English.
그 때 영어에서
최우수 성적을 받으셨죠
I like him.
맘에 드오
Well, in that case, so do I.
그러시다니 다행입니다
I apologise for interjecting myself
in your inspection tour,
먼저 일정에 혼선을 준 것
사과부터 하겠소
but I have a message
for President Fowler.
파울러 대통령께 전할 말이 있소
전화로 직접 하시죠
You could just phone him.
I would like him to hear it from you,
his friend of many years,
그보다는 대통령과 친분이
두터운 당신을 통해
who received it personally from me,
직접 전달이 된다면
and saw my expression and the
language of my body as I spoke it.
내 표정과 몸짓까지도
잘 느낄 수 있으실 거요
I understand.
알겠습니다
Chechnya is an internal affair.
체첸은 우리의 국내 문제니
What we do there should be
none of your concern.
우리가 뭘 하든 참견하지 마시오
I don't think he will agree.
전해드리겠지만
수긍 안 하실 겁니다
Some people in my country
will use this issue to weaken me.
정적들은 내 입지를
약화시키려 하고 있소
Some people in my country say your war
in Chechnya is exactly your weakness.
하지만 체첸 문제 때문에
각하의 입지가 약화된다고 봅니다
It's a nation of criminals.
체첸은 범죄 집단이요
Every day brings another cowardly
attack on innocent Russian citizens.
무고한 러시아 국민들을
매일 공격하고 있소
It is none of your concern.
당신네가 상관할 바 아니오
Stability is our concern.
우린 안정을 원하고
Peace in Chechnya is our concern.
우린 체첸에서의 평화를 원합니다
And, if I may speak frankly...
그리고 솔직히 말씀 드리면...
your control over your military
concerns us, too.
각하의 군부 장악력이
우려가 됩니다
For you to get involved here, it's... like
sleeping with another man's wife.
그런 간섭은 말하자면 뭐랄까
다른 사람의 아내와 자고 나선
And what you are suggesting
is that, afterward,
뻔뻔하게도 한 지붕 아래서
they can all live together
under the same roof.
다 함께 살자고
하는 거나 마찬가지요
But what really happens is
the betrayed husband buys a gun.
하지만 그 남편은
복수의 칼을 갈게 마련이지
- That went well.
- Who's the guy with Nemerov?
- 한 방 먹었군
- 그 옆은 누구죠?
- Anatoli Grushkov.
- Old KGB?
- 아나톨리 그루쉬코프
- 구 KGB요?
He's been around since Brezhnev.
Nobody's had the guts to get rid of him.
브레즈네프 시절부터 있었네
다들 제거하기를 두려워하지
Because he knows
where the bodies are buried?
약점을 다 알기 때문인가요?
He buried them himself.
약점을 만든 장본인이지
And we were able to obtain a roster
of their scientists at Arzamas.
아자마스에서 일하는
과학자들의 명단을 입수했어
Who's who, what their expertise is.
이름과 전문 분야까지 모두
Arzamas-16 is home
이곳 '아자마스-16'은
to the All-Russian Scientific Research
Institute of Experimental Physics
러시아 실험물리
과학연구소의 출발점이자
and is the birthplace
of our first atomic bomb.
첫 원자탄의 탄생지이기도 합니다
Many of our greatest scientists
worked here and many still do.
러시아 최고의 위대한 과학자들이
지금도 일하고 있습니다
Since 1995,
1995년 이래
we have dismantled
over 10,000 nuclear devices.
1만 개 이상의
핵 폭탄을 해체했습니다...
We tried so hard to get in here
over the years.
이곳을 뚫기 위해
그렇게도 애를 썼지
I sent three people.
요원 셋을 보냈지만
They all died trying.
도중에 목숨을 잃었네
What does the T-shirt say?
등에 뭐라고 쓴 거죠?
"I am a bomb technician. If you
see me running... try to catch up."
'난 폭탄 기술자인데, 내가
뛰는 걸 보면... 죽어라 뛰어라'
OK.
가시죠
Sir, I'm sorry. Just one quick thing.
I'm sure it's nothing.
죄송하지만 확인할 게 있어서...
별 거 아닌데요
According to this, there are
17 senior scientists on duty today.
여길 보면 오늘 근무하는
수석 연구원이 총17명인데...
I only count 14.
14명 뿐이더군요
Doctors Milinov, Orlov and Spassky.
They don't seem to be here.
밀리노프 박사, 오를로프 박사
스파스키 박사가 없는 것 같습니다
I will make inquiries.
물어보도록 하죠
Dr. Milinov is out sick.
Orlov is on vacation.
밀리노프는 병가, 오를로프는 휴가
Spassky, I'm grieved to say,
was killed
그리고 스파스키는
슬픈 일이지만...
driving his car to work
just this past week.
지난 주 출근 길
교통 사고로 사망했소
We move on, shall we?
그럼 가실까요?
Please.
이쪽으로
Very impressive. You almost seem
to have that information memorised.
인상적입니다
일일이 다 외운 것 같군요
I assumed you would ask, Dr. Ryan.
물어볼 줄 알고 준비한 거요
이스라엘 하이파
We touch down at Andrews at 2130.
Tell him to meet me there.
앤드류스에 21시 30분 도착이니까
거기서 보자고 하게
Sir? Those three missing scientists.
국장님, 그 세 명 말인데요
Milinov's expertise is detonators.
밀리노프는 뇌관 전문이고
Spassky's expertise
is the nuclear core.
스파스키는 핵심이 전문 분야고
Orlov is a mathematician
오를로프는 수학자로서
whose expertise is the geometry of
high explosives inside a fission bomb.
핵 폭탄의
내폭제 배열 전문가입니다
The exact three men you would need
if you wanted to build a bomb.
폭탄 제조에
꼭 필요한 사람들이로군
- Grushkov said...
- Grushkov's a liar.
- 그루쉬코프 말로는...
- 다 거짓말이네
Milinov is not sick.
Orlov hardly ever takes a vacation
밀리노프는 건강하고
오를로프는 휴가라곤 모르며
and Spassky, who's supposed to
have died driving a car, doesn't drive.
스파스키는 교통 사고로
죽었다지만 운전을 못 하지
They have no idea
where these guys are.
그들도 어디 있는지 모르는 걸세
I'm dying to ask you how you know.
어떻게 아셨는지 궁금하네요
Secure source inside the Kremlin.
크레믈린의 내부 정보원
Codename Spinnaker.
암호명은 스피나커
He gives me stuff, I give him stuff.
서로 필요한 걸 주고 받지
We keep the back channels open
in hopes of staving off disaster.
'재난'을 방지하기 위해 뒤쪽에
마련한 대화 채널 같은 거네
And speaking of disaster,
did you call your girlfriend yet?
자네도 재난이 있지
애인한테 전화는 했나?
No. I don't know how to get out of this.
아뇨, 어떻게
해야 될지 모르겠어요
All right. Invite her to the White House
correspondents' dinner Sunday night.
그럼 일요일 저녁에 열리는
백악관 기자 만찬에 초대하게
It's the hottest ticket in town.
다들 못 가서 안달이지
좋아할 걸세
- Sounds great. How do I get in?
- Trust me.
- 근데 어떻게 들어가죠?
- 나만 믿게
I'll see you at the car.
차에서 기다리게
Still loving your desk job?
아직 사무실이 좋나?
Yeah, I am.
네, 그럼요
How's your Russian?
러시아 말은 여전하고?
Still works. Why?
녹슬지 않았죠, 왜요?
Three Russian nuclear scientists are
missing. I need to know where they are.
세 명의 러시아 핵 물리학자가
사라졌는데 소재를 파악해주게
I wasn't doing this any more.
손 뗀지 오래입니다
I just need information this time,
Johnny.
정보만 캐면 돼, 조니
Your orders are on the plane.
Wheels up at 2330. Have a nice flight.
명령서는 23시 30분에 떠나는
비행기에 있네, 여행 잘 하게
Sunday night, 8.00, at the Hilton. The
tickets are in the name of John Clark.
일요일 밤 8시, 힐튼 호텔
초대권은 존 클라크로 돼 있어
- You do have a tux?
- Yeah, yes, sir.
- 턱시도는 있나?
- 네, 있습니다
My beautiful wife, Julie, is from
New Jersey. 15 electoral votes.
제 아내 줄리는 뉴저지 출신이니
15표는 따놓은 당상이죠
And is, as you know, half-Jewish,
또 유대인 피가 반은 흐르니까
so we'll take Florida's
25 electoral votes and divide by two.
플로리다의 25표 중 반은
우리한테 몰릴 것입니다
- This is a nice hotel.
- Yeah. Beautiful.
- 멋진 호텔인 걸
- 그래, 근사해
My friend Rita stayed here once.
She said it was... nice.
리타란 내 친구도 여기 묵었는데
정말 좋았대
Maybe after dinner we can...
만찬이 끝나면 우리...
we can get a room here.
방 하나 잡을까?
I already did.
벌써 잡았어
- You didn't.
- Yes, I did.
- 설마...
- 진짜라니까
...I did, on a handful of occasions,
smoke marijuana.
저도 마리화나를
피운 적이 있습니다
California, 54 electoral votes.
캘리포니아의 54표도 우리 겁니다
(MOBILE PHONES RING)
At 0600 Moscow time, the Russians
launched a massive artillery strike
모스크바 시간으로 06시
체첸의 수도 그로즈니에 대해
against Grozny,
the capital of Chechnya.
대규모 포격이 가해졌습니다
The shells contained an experimental
chemical weapon, a nerve agent.
개발 중인 신경 가스 계통의
강력한 화학 무기를 썼는데
Saturation, you can see
on the sat photos, took 20 minutes,
위성 사진이 보여주듯
20분에 걸친 확산으로
after which every person
inside a radius of 12 miles
반경 20여 km 내에 있던
모든 사람들이
was rendered helpless by symptoms
approximating late-stage cerebral palsy.
말기 뇌성마비와 유사한
증상을 보이며 희생됐습니다
- Oh, my God.
- How many dead?
- 세상에
- 사망자 수는?
Best guess, 80%.
최소 80% 이상입니다
Nemerov launched the biggest attack
in the history of chemical warfare.
네메로프는 화학전 사상 최대의
공격을 감행한 것입니다
- Let's talk response.
- The worst thing we can do is nothing.
- 대응책은?
- 좌시해서는 안됩니다
If he gets away with chemical weapons,
what's next? Biological, nuclear?
네, 이번 사태를 눈 감아주면
생물학 무기나 핵무기도 쓸 테죠
OK. Short of gassing the Kremlin,
what's the strongest response?
그럼, 같이 독가스를 쓸 순 없고
어떤 방법이 좋겠나?
- We send in peacekeepers.
- Chechnya's not sovereign.
- 평화유지군을 보내죠
- 체첸은 독립국이 아닙니다
They requested recognition. We give it.
Not full diplomatic, provisional.
인정해 달라고 했으니 인정해주고
잠정적인 권리를 부여하는 거죠
Then the Chechens request assistance
and we send in peacekeepers.
그 다음 긴급 지원을 요청하면
평화유지군을 보내면 됩니다
- How do you get them in?
- Fly them in from Turkey.
- 어떻게 들여보내지?
- 터키에서 공수하면 됩니다
- Over Armenian air space?
- To screw Russia? They won't complain.
- 아르메니아 영공으로요?
- 서로 앙숙이니 반길 겁니다
Let's do it. Nemerov can choke on it.
좋네, 네메로프가 자초한 거니까
Bill?
뭔가?
- Dr. Ryan.
- Yes, sir.
- 라이언 박사
- 네
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나?
Conventional wisdom suggests
각하, 상식적으로 생각해 볼 때
that Nemerov is playing
the traditional Russian role.
네메로프도 전임자들과
다를 바 없어 보입니다
Be aggressive, flex your muscles,
dare the world to stop you.
호전적인 무력 시위에
덤빌 테면 덤비라는 식이죠
- But Nemerov isn't conventional.
- He acts like a hardliner.
- 하지만 본심은 아닙니다
- 강경론자처럼 행동을 하잖나?
With respect, I don't think he is one.
하지만 그가 한 짓이 아닙니다
He just gassed the capital of another
country. With respect, you're wrong.
다른 나라의 수도에 독가스를 쐈네
자네 생각이 틀린 거네
- What are we wasting our time for?
- What if he didn't order the attack?
- 전혀 망설일 필요가 없습니다
- 명령을 안 내렸다면요?
What if Nemerov
didn't order the attack?
그가 공격 명령을 안 내렸다면요?
What if it was a... a rogue general?
어떤 무모한... 장군의 짓이라면요?
Or a military unit frustrated
that they couldn't get the rebels out?
아님 반군 소탕에 실패한
어떤 부대의 자의적 행위라면요?
Have you reason to believe he didn't
order it, or are you just floating this?
그렇게 믿을 특별한 이유가 있나
아니면 그냥 흘려보는 건가?
(You don't know.)
자네는 몰라
I don't think he did it, sir.
I would bet he didn't do it.
제 생각에 그렇다는 겁니다
틀림 없이 아닐 겁니다
Will senior staff remain behind
for a few minutes, please?
수석 참모진만 잠깐 남아 주겠소?
(TV) Russia's newly-installed
president, Alexander Nemerov,
러시아에 새로 취임한
알렉산더 네메로프 대통령이
has just begun to address the state.
We join him in progress.
대국민 연설을 시작했는데
지금부터 중계합니다
(APPLAUSE ON TV)
(INTERPRETER) For ten years now,
we have contended...
이제 10년 째 우리 러시아는...
Excuse me. Could you turn that up?
소리 좀 크게 해주시겠습니까?
...toward innocent Russian citizens.
...무고한 러시아 시민들이었죠
(IN RUSSIAN)
Finally...
하지만...
...every nation has a right
to defend itself.
모든 나라에는 자위권이 있습니다
This terrorism must end.
테러는 종식돼야 합니다
The bombing of Chechnya...
was my decision.
공격 명령은 제가 내린 것입니다
Nice going, ace.
빗나갔어요
(RUSSIAN) Who did it?
누가 그랬소?
General Pildysh, General Mitkin.
Unhappy old Communists.
필디쉬 장군, 미트킨 장군입니다
골수 공산주의자들이죠
Bastards.
망할 놈들
- Relieve them of command.
- I will shoot them myself.
- 지휘권을 박탈하시오
- 총살시키겠습니다
Just disappear them.
안 보이게만 하시오
Their execution would tell the world
I didn't have control.
처형은 군부를 장악하지
못했음을 알리는 꼴이니까
These days, better to appear guilty
than impotent.
나약하게 보이기 보단
차라지 누명을 쓰는 게 낫소
How is our Russian friend
affected by this?
우리의 러시아 친구는
어떨 지 모르겠소
I am not affected.
I remain devoted to our little plan.
난 흔들리지 않아요
내 동지 의식은 확고하죠
At what you're charging us,
I am not surprised.
요구 금액을 보자면
아주 당연한 거요
- And the American?
- Mr. Mason is a believer.
- 미국 쪽은 어때요?
- 메이슨 씨는 믿을 만하오
I put a little extra
in the escrow account for him.
수고비보다 좀 더 많이 보내줬소
- Why?
- He won't live long enough to get it.
- 이유는?
- 보지도 못하고 죽을 테니까
- Where is the package?
- It left Haifa a week ago.
- '물건'은 어디 있소?
- 1주일 전 하이파를 떠났죠
I'm told these things can kill you.
이것도 사람을 죽인다죠?
But so much has changed.
하지만 그 동안 변화가 많았죠
Perhaps the new situation suggests
we consider... a different approach?
새로운 상황이니 만큼
새로운 접근법이 필요하지 않겠소?
Maybe try to bring Russia
more into Europe,
러시아를 유럽으로 더 끌어 들이고
more into our way of thinking?
우리 노선에 동조케 하면 어때요?
We have discussed that,
Monsieur Monceau,
이미 끝난 얘기요, 몬소 씨
and with your concurrence, rejected it.
당신도 거기에 동의하지 않았소?
Oh. Perhaps we were hasty.
성급하지 않았나 싶군요
- Perhaps our plan is...
- Is what?
- 우리가 세운 계획은...
- 계획 뭐요?
Not perfectly conceived.
출발이 잘못된 것 같아요
(IN GERMAN) Are you crazy?
All over the world, right-wing parties,
무슨 헛소리요? 전세계에 걸쳐
우익 정당
nationalist movements,
Nazis, Aryan Nations,
민족주의 단체, 나치주의자
'아리아 네이션' 모두
all working together for the first time.
사상 처음 손을 잡았소
Is that not perfect?
그게 잘못된 거요?
Well, I respect the will and judgment
of my friends.
여러분의 목표와 판단을
존중하는 바이지만
But in light of the week's events,
I am grown...
지난 주에 일어난
사태를 지켜 본 뒤로...
uncomfortable with this plan.
의구심이... 생기게 됐고
So I must... beg your leave.
그러니 난... 그만 빠지겠소
Gentlemen.
그럼 이만
Herr Haft will help you out.
하프트 씨가 배웅할 거요
Your scarf, Monsieur.
스카프 하셔야죠
메릴랜드주 볼티모어
Watch it with that thing.
You're gonna kill somebody.
조심해서 해, 누구 죽일 일 있어?
Yo, what's up, Mason?
왔나, 메이슨?
I always wanted to ask you.
Where'd you get that tat, man?
전부터 물어보고 싶었는데
그 문신 어디서 했어?
- The navy.
- The navy? I was in the navy.
해군에 있을 때
그래? 나도 해군에 있었어
Hospital ship, six years. You?
병원선에서 6년 있었지, 자넨?
Eight months.
8개월
Oh. You wash out?
도중에 쫓겨났군?
All right, brother.
You have a good one.
갈게 형제, 멋진 문신이야
Yeah, brother.
그래, 형제
그 날이 왔네, 수고하게
(TV)... not realising the rest of the world
is watching and will take a cue from us.
우리 미국의 행동에 우방국들도
함께 동참할 것입니다
The unprecedented attack
on Chechnya
전례 없는 이번 만행은
signals a dangerous
and troubling shift in Russian policy.
러시아 정책상의 염려스러운
변화를 보여주는 바
It demands the toughest and most
unambiguous response from the West.
이는 서방의 명확하고 강력한
대응을 요구하고 있습니다
NATO forces are on their way to
Chechnya to serve as peacekeepers
체첸에 도착하는 대로 나토 군은
평화유지의 임무와 더불어
and to provide humanitarian aid
to victims of this monstrous...
가공할 비극의 희생자들에게
구호 활동을 펼칠 것이며...
(SWITCHES OFF TV)
(IN RUSSIAN) I expected this.
예상하던 바요
Really?
정말요?
- What will you do?
- Nothing.
어쩔 건데요?
어쩌긴
We will do nothing.
그냥 구경만 할 거요
These are four hours old. Russian
12th, 15th and 2nd tank regiments.
4시간 전에 찍은 건데
12, 15, 그리고 2기갑 연대야
Why haven't they moved?
꼼짝도 안 했어, 왜지?
- Nemerov's too smart to move them.
- He speaks.
- 네메로프는 어리석지 않아
- 입 열었네
Jack, Nemerov's got 19,000 tanks.
No way NATO can match that.
잭, 러시아가 보유한 1만 9천대의
탱크에 나토 군은 맞설 수 없어
That's why he's not gonna move them.
그래서 움직이지 않는 거야
It's like chess.
He's thinking three moves ahead.
체스 같은 거야
세 수나 내다 보고 있어
The NATO playbook says we can only
stop him with tactical nuclear weapons.
나토 교본에 따르면 우리는
전술 핵무기로나 상대할 수 있어
And he won't risk a nuclear war
over this.
이 일로 핵 전쟁까지
원하진 않을 걸
I also think he's sending us
a message. He didn't bomb Grozny.
메시지를 보내는 거야
그가 한 짓이 아냐
러시아 아자마스-16
(IN RUSSIAN) Excuse me.
I'm looking for Mrs. Spassky.
실례합니다만 스파스키 부인은요?
At the end of the corridor.
복도 끝이에요
(IN RUSSIAN) I haven't seen Sasha
since university.
대학 졸업 후엔 보질 못했어요
And you were his teaching assistant?
Strange, I don't remember you.
진짜 내 아들 조교였수?
이상하네, 기억이 안 나는데
When he heard I was in Arzamas,
he asked me to look in on you.
제가 아자마스에 있다니까
한 번 찾아 뵈라고 했어요
(THEY SPEAK RUSSIAN)
- He says he'll take me to the West.
- That would require a lot of money.
- 날 외국으로 데려간댔다우
- 돈 많이 들 텐데요
Just because the imbeciles here pay
him nothing doesn't mean others won't.
쥐꼬리만한 월급으로 부려먹지
않는 사람들도 있게 마련이거든
He has a secret job.
비밀스런 일을 한다우
For the government?
정부 일인가요?
For imbeciles with money.
돈 많은 어떤 멍청이 일이지
Same nonsense, do this, don't do that.
거기서도 똑같아
이건 해라, 저건 하지 마라
They even told him
not to call his mother.
엄마한테도 전화하지 말랬다지
The pigs.
망할 놈들
I could die any day
and he can't phone his mother.
어미가 죽을 날만 기다리는데
전화도 못하게 하다니
But my Sasha, he called.
그렇지만 사샤는 전화를 했다우
Just last night.
바로 어젯밤에
Clark got us her number. NSA traced
calls to that number back to here.
클라크가 준 번호를 NSA에서
추적한 결과 여기가 발신지입니다
It's an abandoned Soviet army base
on the Kremenchug reservoir.
크레멘추그 저수지 옆의
폐쇄된 소련군 기지죠
What are three Russian atomic
scientists doing in Ukraine?
러시아 핵 물리학자들이
우크라이나에서 뭘 하지?
A fair guess, they're building a bomb.
폭탄을 만들고 있겠죠
Nemerov has thousands of bombs.
Why would he build a secret one?
이미 수천 개나 있는데
왜 그렇게 몰래 만들죠?
Deniability.
오리발 용이지
Build one nobody knows about, he can
drive it to Chechnya in his Beemer.
비밀리에 제조해서 체첸으로
몰래 운반할 속셈인 거네
No way to track it, no way to trace it.
제조 장소와 과정도 숨길 수 있고
He could set it off and say,
"I didn't do it."
폭파시킨 후 모른다고 발뺌하겠지
With respect, I don't think
that adds up.
제 생각엔 별로 가능성이 없는데요
It adds up. You just don't like
what it adds up to.
가능성은 충분해
자넨 그 결과가 두려운 걸세
(IN RUSSIAN) Ah, the warmth
of plutonium decay.
플루토늄 붕괴의 이 따스함
It's completely corroded.
At least you're wearing gloves.
완전히 부식됐군
장갑을 끼어 그나마 다행이지
Anyone want to light up
an American cigarette?
미국 담배 한 대 피울 사람 있나?
You're crazy.
제정신인가?
I'm going out.
나가면 되잖나
The explosive blocks
must be replaced.
기폭 장치는 교체가 불가피합니다
Machined to a thousandth
of a millimetre
엄밀한 수학적 배열에 따라
in a mathematically determined
configuration.
0.001mm 이하의 오차만이 허용되죠
- Do we have a bomb?
- First we must analyse the yield...
- 사용할 수 있겠소?
- 먼저 핵 출력을 분석해야...
Do we have a bomb?
사용할 수 있겠소?
Yes.
됩니다
Yes, we do.
네, 가능해요
(PHONE RINGS)
This is a... a test.
이건... 시험일 뿐이야
Answer it.
대답해
- Answer it.
- Are you sure?
- 어서
- 괜찮겠어?
Hello?
여보세요?
Yes.
네
Yes, sir.
알겠습니다
I have to go outside for just a second.
나갔다 올게, 잠깐이면 돼
OK? I'll be right back.
괜찮지? 금방 올게
I'll be right back.
금방 올 거야
- Sir, I write reports.
- I reviewed your military records.
- 전 분석가입니다
- 자네의 군 기록을 살펴봤네
- You can take care of yourself.
- Yes, sir. But I'm not trained for that.
- 앞가림은 할 수 있겠어
- 하지만 훈련도 안 받았습니다
I'm not asking you to be an operations
officer, just my eyes and ears. I can't go.
작전을 수행하란 말이 아냐
가서 내 눈과 귀가 되어 달란 거네
So... this isn't sanctioned.
그럼 비밀 임무군요
I want you to give this to Clark,
see what he finds out, bring it home.
이걸 클라크에게 준 뒤
입수된 정보를 가져오면 돼
Yes, sir.
알겠습니다
Jack...
잭
...
we never had this discussion.
우린 안 만난 거네
What discussion?
누가 만나요?
우크라이나 크레멘추그 저수지
OK. Clark...
So this is three days ago.
자요, 클라크
3일 전에 찍은 겁니다
It shows vehicles here.
Guards here and here.
차량들은 여기에 있고
경비병은 여기, 여기에 있죠
I gotta get one of those.
탐나는 장비인 걸
Now, the infrared satellite
took this photograph 34 hours ago.
그리고 이건 34시간 전에
적외선 위성으로 포착한 겁니다
That shows guards here and here.
경비병이 여기, 여기에 있습니다
I don't even have e-mail.
난 e-메일도 없지
There are two at the checkpoint,
between two and five in the barracks
초소에 두 명
막사에는 둘에서 다섯
and two with the package,
which we believe to be here.
'물건' 주변에 두 명
바로 여기 있을 겁니다
No problem. Give me a couple
of guys, some tranquilliser darts,
문제 없소, 요원 몇 명에
마취 총만 있으면
we can be out in six minutes.
6분 내로 다 끝나지
- There is a problem.
- What's that?
- 근데 문제가 있어요
- 뭐요?
This is yesterday.
No guards visible at all.
이건 어제 찍은 건데
경비병들이 안 보입니다
Why is that a problem, Mr. Ryan?
그게 왜 문제요, 라이언 씨?
For two reasons. Either we can't
see them, which is bad,
첫째, 안에 있는데도
포착되지 않은 경우이거나
or worse, they left, and we're too late.
둘째, 일을 마치고
떠났다는 얘기니까요
Suit up.
복장 갖추시오
- What?
- You can't go dressed like that.
- 네?
- 그런 차림으로 갈 거요?
No, no. I'm an analyst.
I don't go on missions.
모르는 모양인데, 난 분석가지
현장 요원이 아닙니다
Relax, 007. It's not a mission.
It's just a recce.
염려 마시오 007, 공격 임무가
아니라 정찰일 뿐이니까
Fine, whatever you call it.
I don't do that. I write reports.
뭐라고 하든 난 안 가요
난 보고서만 쓰면 되니까요
OK. So write a report about it. Suit up.
좋소, 그럼 보고서에 쓰시오
복장 갖춰요
Clark, no.
클라크, 싫어요
Clark... no.
클라크... 싫다니까요
Cabot tells me you got my ticket
to the correspondents' dinner.
국장님이 그러던데
백악관 만찬에 나 대신 갔다던데?
Have a good time?
I've never been to one of those.
즐거웠소? 나도 처음이라서
I was actually looking forward to it.
잔뜩 기대에 부풀었었는데
Clark, no. I'm not going in there.
클라크, 난 안 들어갈 겁니다
Goddamn right. You're gonna stay here
and make sure no one steals my boat.
당신 말이 맞소, 내 보트를
지킬 사람도 필요하니까
Be right back.
금방 오겠소
Damn.
젠장
하이파
(THEY SHOUT IN UKRAINIAN)
(UKRAINIAN)
Oh, Jesus.
이런 세상에
Oh, God. Immigration
didn't call you guys, huh?
맙소사, 이민국에서
연락 못 받았어요?
(SHOUTS IN UKRAINIAN)
I'm sorry. You speak English?
I don't speak much Ukrainian.
미안하지만 영어 해요?
난 여기 말 몰라요
It's not what you think. I'm American.
I have papers...
난 미국인이에요, 그런 사람
아닙니다, 허가서도 여기에 있...
- (SHOUT IN UKRAINIAN)
- OK. No papers.
네, 가만 있을게요
- (UKRAINIAN)
- Please. Just put the gun down.
제발, 총은 내려 놓고 합시다
The light? You want me
to put the light down?
이 손전등요? 내려 놓으라고요?
OK. Take it easy.
I'll put the light down.
알았어요, 진정해요
내려 놓겠습니다
Here we go, I'm putting it down.
자, 내려 놓습니다
Shoot him, Ryan.
쏴요, 라이언
Shoot him.
어서
Shoot him before he figures out
what I'm saying.
쏘라는 말을 눈치 채기 전에
어서 쏴 버려요
- Get their shoes.
- What?
- 신발 챙겨요
- 네?
Tell them to take their shoes off.
어서 신발 벗으라고 해요
(SPEAKS UKRAINIAN)
- You speak Ukrainian.
- Yeah. You don't?
- 꽤 유창하시군
- 네, 못하세요?
Whatever it is they were spray painting
was big, about the size of a fridge.
페인트 흔적을 보건대
냉장고 정도의 큰 물건이었소
The imprint it left was deep.
We know three things.
칠 자국이 두터웠지
여기서 분명한 사실은
It was heavy, something was
radioactive, and now it's gone.
그 무거운 물건이 방사능 물질이며
이젠 사라졌단 거요
- One of them spoke English?
- South African.
- 한 쪽이 영어를 썼댔죠?
- 남아공 사람이었소
So, what's a South African
doing in the Ukraine
그럼, 남아공 사람이
러시아 과학자들과
with three Russian scientists
and a crate from Israel?
이스라엘에서 온
물건을 놓고 뭘 한 거죠?
- Tell Cabot I'll call him from Haifa.
- Better hurry.
- 하이파에서 연락한다고 하시오
- 서두르는 게 좋겠어요
Most people believe the 20th century
was defined by the death struggle
사람들은 20세기를 평가할 때
공산주의와 자본주의의
of communism versus capitalism
치열한 대결로 특징짓는 반면
and that fascism was but a hiccup.
파시즘은 무시하는 경향이 있소
Today we know better.
성급한 평가였지
Communism was a fool's errand. The
followers of Marx, gone from this earth.
공산주의는 다 부질 없었소
마르크스의 추종자들은 사라졌지만
But the followers of Hitler
abound and thrive.
히틀러의 추종자들은
지금 번성을 하고 있소
Hitler, however,
had one great disadvantage.
당시엔 여건 상
불리한 점이 있었지
He lived in a time when fascism,
like a virus,
히틀러가 살던 시기에
퍼뜨려진 파시즘은
like the AIDS virus,
에이즈 바이러스처럼
needed a strong host in order to spread.
Germany was that host.
강력한 숙주가 있어야 전파될 수
있었고 그 숙주가 독일이었소
But strong as it was,
Germany could not prevail.
하지만 하나의
국가만으로는 역부족이었지
The world was too big.
세계는 거대했으니까
Fortunately, the world has changed.
다행히도 세계는 이제 변했소
Global communications,
cable TV, the internet.
범세계적 통신망과
케이블 TV, 인터넷을 통해
Today the world is smaller
오늘날의 세계는 작아졌고
and the virus does not need
a strong host in order to spread.
바이러스의 전파에도 강력한
숙주가 필요하지 않게 됐소
This virus...
이 바이러스는...
is airborne.
공중으로 전파되니까
One more thing.
Let no man call us crazy.
마지막으로 한 마디
우린 미치광이가 아니오
They called Hitler crazy, but Hitler
wasn't crazy. He was stupid.
다들 히틀러를 미치광이라고
하지만 그는 어리석었을 뿐이었소
You don't fight Russia and America.
러시아와 미국에 맞섰으니까
You get Russia and America
to fight each other
그보단 그 둘을 맞서게 함으로써
함께 제거해야 했소
and destroy each other.
- What did you find?
- Ukraine's exports are online.
- 뭘 알아냈어?
- 다행히 인터넷에 올라 있어서
I pulled up the shipping manifests.
적하 목록을 입수했는데
The only crate that size
was picked up at Kiev ten days ago
조건에 들어맞는 화물이 있었어
열흘 전 키에프 공항에서
and flown to the Canary Islands.
카나리아 제도로 발송됐지
The air force
has a nuclear assessment...
공군에 핵 점검 팀이
있으니까 연락해서...
Jack, it got put on a cargo freighter
headed for the East Coast.
잭, 잠깐만
거기서 다시 미 동부로 선적됐어
- What?
- Baltimore. It's coming here.
- 뭐?
- 볼티모어로, 여기에 올 거야
It's a great view from the Budweiser
blimp as we count down to game time.
경기가 시작되기 전의 모습이
비행선에서 멋지게 포착됐습니다
We'll have the pre-game festivities
경기 전 행사가 열릴 텐데요
as well as the arrival of the nation's
No. 1 football fan in a moment.
잠시 후에는 미국 최고의
풋볼 팬이 등장하실 겁니다
♪ Then conquer we must
우리는 승리할 겁니다
♪ For our cause it is just
정의로운 명분이 있으니까요
♪ And this be our motto
우리의 마음에 새겨요
하느님을 향한 우리의 믿음을
♪ In God is our trust
♪ And the star-spangled banner
별이 가득한 성조기는
♪ Forever shall wave
영원히 휘날립니다
♪ O'er the land of the free...
이 자유의 대지 위로...
Get me the duty officer!
어서 당직관 대줘
♪ Home of the brave ♪
용감한 이들의 고향 위로
(CROWD CHEERS)
Ladies and gentlemen,
the President of the United States,
관중 여러분
우리 미 합중국을 대표하는
Robert Fowler!
파울러 대통령이십니다
(BOOING AND CHEERING)
Showtime.
시작해보세
Shit.
제기랄
15 yard penalty, first down.
15야드 벌칙, 퍼스트 다운
- That's the way!
- (MOBILE PHONE RINGS)
잘 한다
Shit.
젠장
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello.
여보세요
- Hello?
- Sir!
- 여보세요?
- 국장님
- Hello?
- Sir!
- 여보세요?
- 국장님
Shit!
제기랄
(PHONE RINGS)
- Cabot.
- It's Ryan.
- 캐봇입니다
- 라이언입니다
- What?
- The bomb is in play.
- 뭐?
- 핵 폭탄이 들어왔습니다
The AFRAT team are meeting me at
the docks in 20 minutes to try to find it.
공군 핵 점검 팀이 20분 후 부두에
도착해서 저와 수색을 벌일 겁니다
- What docks?
- Baltimore.
- 부두? 그게 어딘가?
- 볼티모어 항요
- You're breaking up. What did you say?
- Baltimore.
- 감이 멀어져, 뭐라고?
- 볼티모어 항요
- I'm losing you. I'll call you back...
- Baltimore.
- 잘 안 들려, 내가 걸지
- 볼티모어 항요
Sir!
국장님
볼티모어 포럼에 잘 오셨습니다
John! Red-Green! Let's go! Let's go!
존, 비상이다! 여기서 나가, 어서
Move it! Let's go!
빨리, 어서
Move! Go, go, go, go! Move!
어서, 빨리, 빨리, 어서 움직여
What the hell is going on?
대체 무슨 일인가?
Some Russian scientists made
a nuclear bomb. It's in Baltimore.
러시아 과학자들이 만든 핵 폭탄이
오늘 아침 도시로 반입됐답니다
- Get those people out of the stadium.
- Stay down!
- 관중들을 대피시켜
- 엎드려 계십시오
(TV) The President
has been taken off the field.
대통령께서 경기장에서
급히 나가셨습니다
- 407.
- Thanks, JJ.
- 407
- 고마워
Something has happened
of tremendous proportions.
뭔가 거대한 사건이
발생했음은 분명합니다
We have no word as to what, but
there is an enormous cloud over...
구체적으로 밝혀진 건 없지만
엄청난 구름이 피어 오르고...
Go, go, go!
어서 움직여, 어서, 어서
Mr. President! Are you all right?
대통령 각하, 괜찮으십니까?
He's stuck. Get out of the way.
차에 끼셨다, 반대 쪽으로
Mr. President, are you all right?
각하, 괜찮으십니까?
Are you all right, Mr. President?
This is the Marines, sir.
괜찮으십니까, 각하?
저희는 해병대입니다
I need your help.
이리 와, 대니
Alvarez, get me a stretcher, now!
알바레즈, 들것 가져와, 어서
You got the stretcher?
들것 없나?
- You got the stretcher?
- No, I don't want one.
- 들것 없나?
- 됐네, 걸을 수 있네
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
자, 가자, 어서 탑승 해
Move it!
모두 철수
모두 탑승 해
Go, go! Close them off! Go on up!
빨리 와, 문 닫아, 출발
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
(IN RUSSIAN) Mr. President.
대통령 각하
There's been a nuclear explosion
in America. Come with us now.
미국에서 핵 폭발이 있었습니다
오셔야 겠습니다
What?
뭐?
We don't know who or how.
But it wasn't us.
어떻게 된 건지 모르지만
우리는 아닙니다
After Grozny, you hope it wasn't us.
체첸도 그랬고... 장담할 순 없지
We are drafting
a strong denial for you.
부인하는 글을 작성 중입니다
And a statement of sympathy.
위로의 글도 잊지 말고
And Yuri... order all military
on the alert.
그리고 유리
전군에 비상 경계령을 내리게
(FAINT VOICES ON RADIO)
Hey! It's Ryan.
라이언입니다
- Jack, where are you?
- Somewhere outside Baltimore.
- 잭, 어디야?
- 볼티모어 외곽인 것 같아요
- Cabot got the President out.
- Where is he now?
- 국장이 대통령을 탈출 시켰어
- 지금 어디 계신데요?
They're taking him airborne, on NAOC.
They think it might be the Russians.
공중 작전 센터기로 모시고 있어
러시아의 소행으로 추측하고 있어
It wasn't the Russians. I gotta talk
to Cabot. Can you patch me through?
러시아가 아니에요, 국장님과
통화하게 비행기에 연결해 줘요
We don't know where Cabot is.
Can you call back in an hour?
거기 없어, 현재 소재 파악이 안돼
한 시간 후에 다시 전화 해
We don't have an hour.
Fowler's gonna want to hit back now.
그럴 시간 없어요, 대통령께서
언제 반격을 가할 지 몰라요
Listen. We have to prove it wasn't the
Russians before he's convinced it is.
그걸 막으려면 먼저 러시아가
아니란 걸 입증해야 돼요
Can you get back to Langley?
본부로 올 수 있겠어?
There's no time. The radiation
assessment team, where are they?
그럴 시간 없어요
핵 점검 팀은 어디 있어요?
- Stambler Tunnels, south of the city.
- (SIRENS)
시 남쪽의 스탬블러 터널이야
The winds are blowing the fallout
to the east and north.
현재 낙진이 바람을 타고
동쪽과 북쪽으로 이동하니까
If you stay south, you're OK.
남쪽으로 가면 안전해
- Mr. President, are you all right?
- How the hell do you think I am?
- 각하, 괜찮으십니까?
- 내가 괜찮을 거라고 보나?
- How many casualties?
- We don't know.
- 사망자 수는?
- 모릅니다
- How the hell did it get there?
- We don't know. Radar didn't pick it up.
- 어떻게 사전에 알지 못했나?
- 글쎄요, 미사일은 아니었습니다
- Well, how is Cabot? Where is he?
- I don't know.
- 캐봇 국장은 어디에 있나?
- 모릅니다
- What do you know?
- I don't know, all right? I don't know!
- 아는 게 뭔가?
- 없습니다, 네, 다 몰라요
I don't know!
나도 알면 좋겠습니다!
- General, Kondor is not on board.
- Send the AFRAT team.
- 장군님, '콘도르'는 없습니다
- 핵 점검 팀 출동 시켜
각하, 데프콘-2를
발령하셔야 합니다
- We should move to DEFCON-2.
- Where's our intelligence?
이렇게 당하다니, 현 상황은?
- Russian air defences are on alert.
- They're afraid of being attacked!
러시아 방공망에
경계령이 내려졌습니다
공격 당할까 봐 그런 거겠지
망할 놈의 의자가 왜 이래!
Sir, we're about to take off.
이륙하겠습니다
- We don't know who did it...
- We think the Russians...
- 누구의 소행인지도 모릅니다...
- 아무래도 러시아가...
- You think?
- Sir, DEFCON-2.
- 아무래도?
- 데프콘-2를 내리십시오
- We're groping in the dark...
- This is too much goddamn bullshit!
- 현재로선 오리무중...
- 어떻게 이런 염병할 일이 있나!
And not enough fact.
아무 것도 모르다니
(TV) The blast crater is about
100, 150 yards wide,
폭발 구덩이의 직경이
100에서 150m 정도임을 볼 때
which suggests a low-yield device,
소형인 것으로 추정되는 바
quite a bit smaller
than the Hiroshima bomb.
히로시마 원폭에 비해
훨씬 작은 거죠
A quarter of a square mile
around the stadium is just gone.
경기장 주변 4백 미터 이내는
완전히 사라졌고
Beyond that, buildings remain, heavily
damaged, for another quarter mile.
그 다음 4백 미터 지역에선
건물들이 위태롭게 서 있으며
The damage tapers off
the farther you get...
거리가 멀어질수록
그 피해 규모도 적어집니다
(PHONE RINGS)
Dubinin.
듀비닌이오
Herr Haft has left for America.
Now we are counting on you.
하프트 씨는 미국으로 떠났소
이제 당신만 믿겠소
I assure you,
I will earn every pfennig.
다시 말하지만 내 몫은 다 하겠소
(RUSSIAN) Attention.
차렷
You've heard of the bomb in the USA.
미국 소식은 다 들었겠지?
What you haven't heard
is that 15 minutes ago
하지만 15분 전 미국 미사일이
an American ICBM hit Moscow.
모스크바에 떨어진
사실은 모를 거다
We are to retaliate against an American
aircraft carrier in the North Sea.
이제 그 복수를 위해 북해상의
미 함공모함을 공격하도록 하겠다
Man your aircraft.
어서 출격 준비해
(SIREN)
The ash isn't radioactive.
The wind's blowing the fallout to sea.
재에는 방사능이 없으며
바람을 타고 바다로 불어갑니다
Captain. Jack Ryan, CIA.
대위님, CIA의 잭 라이언입니다
Lorna Shiro. You need to wait outside.
로나 쉬로입니다
밖에서 기다리십시오
I need to know all you know
about the bomb.
현재까지 알아낸 걸 알려주시죠
We're collecting samples. Get in line.
We'll have the report out tomorrow.
샘플을 채취하고 있으니 분석이
끝나면 내일 보고서가 나갈 겁니다
I need to know now
where this bomb came from,
대위님, 폭탄의
제조처를 알아야 합니다
or even where it didn't come from,
or there may not be a tomorrow.
제조처가 아닌 곳도 좋고요
내일은 안 올 지도 모릅니다
Shit. Wesson, where are you?
젠장, 웨슨, 어디야?
Quarter mile from Ground Zero.
폭심지에서 4백 미터쯤 되는데
This is about as far as we go.
My feet are sizzling.
더 이상 못 가겠어요
발에서 지글지글 소리가 나요
I'm getting rads
nearly the limit of our gear.
더 이상 방사능 노출에
견딜 수 없습니다
- OK. Cut the rover loose and get out.
- Roger that.
- 좋아, 그럼 중단하고 나와
- 알겠습니다
The crate the bomb was shipped in.
Somebody had to sign for it at port.
딜론, 화물 상자는 누군가의
서명이 있어야 하역 될 수 있어
Customs has a database.
Get me a name. Where's Cabot?
세관 기록에 있을 테니
알아봐 줘, 국장님은?
No one knows.
We're checking the hospitals.
몰라, 병원들을 알아보고 있어
- Tried Memorial?
- He wouldn't be there.
- 메모리얼 병원은?
- 거긴 없을 걸...
No, I mean... Is it still...
내 말은... 건물이 어떤지...
It's Cathy's hospital.
캐시가 근무하거든
As far as I know it's still there.
Phones are down.
무너지진 않은 걸로 아는데
전화는 불통이야
Can you keep checking? Thanks.
알았어, 계속 알아봐 줘, 고마워
They could have launched
a Cruise missile.
발사된 크루즈 미사일을
포착 못했을 수도 있네
- We don't know it's Russia.
- Or that it's not.
- 잠깐, 러시아가 아닐 수 있지
- 맞을 수도 있고
If they were sending us a message,
they'd want us to know it was them.
내정 간섭 말라는 의사 표시라면
이렇게 몰래 할 이유가 없을 테죠
Except they could inspire
the confusion we're going through now.
연막을 피워 우릴 혼란에
빠뜨리는 건지도 모르지
Mr. President, we're uplinked.
각하, 연결 됐습니다
President Nemerov, there has been a
major nuclear event in the United States.
네메로프 대통령님, 방금 전
미 동부에서 핵 폭발이 있었습니다
- Loss of life is severe.
- It was no accident.
엄청난 사상자가 발생했죠
- 계획적인 것이죠
- 계획적인 것입니다
- It was not an accident.
- We don't know where it came from.
아직 누구의 소행인지도 모르며...
We have not yet ascertained
the source of this weapon...
그 폭탄의 출처 또한 확인이
안된 상태입니다, 분명한 건...
We have not yet ascertained
the source of this weapon.
그 폭탄의 출처 또한
확인이 안된 상태입니다
But rest assured those responsible
will be dealt with most severely.
분명한 건 누가 한 짓이건
철저히 응징 되리란 것입니다
He's fishing.
우릴 떠보는군
Send our reply.
답신 보내
Whoa, that was a little fast.
저런, 빨리도 보냈군
"Accept the deepest sympathies
of the Russian people.
'러시아 국민들을 대표해
심심한 조의를 표합니다'
"If it was deliberate,
this is a crime without precedent.
'계획된 거라면 이는
초유의 범죄 행위입니다'
"What madman would do such a thing
and why?
'어떤 미치광이가
왜 그런 짓을 했을까요?'
"Russia had nothing to do
with this infamous act."
'러시아는 이번 일과 관련이
없음을 분명히 밝힙니다'
It's canned.
He prepared that in advance.
만들어뒀군, 준비해둔 겁니다
President Nemerov, we've no reason
to suspect Russian involvement...
대통령님, 러시아가
관련됐다고 믿을 이유는
...at this time...
아직 없습니다만...
...but we will protect ourselves
from further aggression.
더 이상 당하고 있지 만은
않을 것을 분명히 해둡니다
He thinks we did this.
우리를 의심하는군
We must demonstrate
the strength of our weapons.
우리의 군 역량을 보여줘야 합니다
They have to understand that
attacking Russia would be suicide.
우리에 대한 공격은
자살 행위임을 알게 될 겁니다
Increase the alert status.
경계 태세를 강화하게
TAO, EW. I'm picking up
intermittent radar, bearing 020.
레이다에 020 방향으로부터
간헐적인 신호가 포착됩니다
Where?
어디?
Now it's gone.
사라졌습니다
(RUSSIAN)
There. It's a weak signal.
보세요, 약합니다
TAO, inbound contact.
미사일을 조준합니다
Multiples-same bearing.
동 방향에 다수의 미사일
- Vampire, vampire!
- Fast movers!
- 뱀파이어!
- 빠르게 접근합니다
I got seven, eight, nine of them!
일곱, 여덟, 총 아홉입니다
The missiles definitely came
from Russian aircraft.
러시아 항공기에서
발사된 것만은 틀림 없네
Grennel can save the ship,
but flight ops are out.
침몰은 면했지만
출격은 불가능하다고 합니다
(RUSSIAN OVER RADIO)
I ordered no such attack.
내 명령이 아니었습니다
You must not respond to this action...
진상 조사가 끝날 때까지
대응을 자제해주기 바랍니다
"...until we investigate all possibilities."
'...대응을 자제해주기 바랍니다'
Like you did in Chechnya?
체첸에 대해서도 그랬잖습니까?
Mr. President, who is in control
of your armed forces?
대통령님, 거기선
누가 군을 지휘합니까?
You dropped the bomb on Hiroshima.
원자폭탄을 히로시마와
You dropped the bomb on Nagasaki.
나가사키에 투하한 게 누구죠?
Do not lecture me on Chechnya.
우리보다 나을 게 없습니다
"...lecture me on Chechnya."
'...나을 게 없습니다'
Mr. President, we are now at a
de facto state of war with the Russians.
각하, 이제 러시아와 사실상의
전쟁 상태에 들어간 겁니다
John Clark was in Haifa yesterday.
We have to find him right away.
클라크는 어제만 해도 하이파에
있었어요, 소재를 파악해야 돼요
Wow.
Look at that gadolinium reading.
이 가돌리늄 수치 좀 봐
The mass fraction is huge!
질량 분율이 엄청 나
OK, connect me to Dillon. I'll hold.
네, 딜론 연결해요, 기다릴 게요
There it is. Savannah River.
그래, '사바나 리버'였어
- Oh, yeah.
- Oh, yeah, what?
- 그래
- 뭐가 그래요?
Gadolinium problem. Hanford always
generates too much promethium.
가돌리늄 문제로 고심했죠
핸포드에서 쓰던 다른 방법은
프로메튬을 과다 발생시키고요
Can you translate that into English?
잠깐, 알아듣게 설명해주시죠
This plutonium came from the DOE
plant at Savannah River, February '68,
이 플루토늄은 68년 2월에
사바나 리버의 핵 처리 공장 내
from K reactor. We even know
which part of K reactor.
K 반응로에서 제조된 것인데
세부적인 사항도 알 수 있죠
- Wait. This is our plutonium?
- Made in the USA.
- 그럼 우리가 만든 겁니까?
- 미국산 제품이죠
Dillon, you've got to find Cabot.
딜론, 국장님을 찾아야 돼
Are you advocating we launch
a first strike?
그렇다면 선제 공격을
하자는 말인가?
It is not a first strike! There's already
been a first strike, and a second.
선제 공격은 저들이 했어
이미 두 번째 공격도 했고
- Don't you get it?
- No, I don't get it!
- 그래도 모르겠나?
- 그래, 모르겠네
I don't understand why we have
to nuke them! It's not reasonable.
왜 핵 공격을 해야 하는지
모르겠네, 그건 말이 안돼
Sidney, goddamn it! They practically
sank an aircraft carrier!
시드니, 그만 두게!
항공모함이 침몰될 뻔했단 말이네
Their missile silos are hot.
We're getting bullshit from Nemerov.
저들은 미사일 격납고를 열어 놓고
거짓말만 해대고 있어
Let's not forget how this started.
They tried to kill me, remember?
이 일이 어떻게 시작됐나?
날 죽이려 했단 말일세
Don't tell me to be reasonable!
말도 안 된다는 소린 집어 치워
(PA S YS TEM) Come to the triage tent
on the side of the building.
건물 옆의 부상자
분류 막사로 오십시오
We will help you find
who you are looking for,
실종자 문의는 그곳에서 하세요
but we are low on blood supply.
현재 혈액이 부족한 상태입니다
Sir?
국장님
Hi.
자네군
What?
네?
- President?
- The President's fine.
- 각하는?
- 무사하십니다
He's fine. Sir...
안심하세요, 국장님...
The bomb. The plutonium...
그 폭탄의 플루토늄은...
- Wife.
- What?
- 아내
- 네?
Wife.
내 아내
Your wife? I'm sure she's fine.
She's in DC.
사모님요? 무사할 겁니다
워싱턴에 계시니까요
The blast radius wasn't that...
폭파 반경이 그렇게...
It wasn't that wide.
크지 않았어요
Sir, listen to me.
국장님, 잘 들으세요
The plutonium was ours.
플루토늄은 우리 거랍니다
John Clark's in Haifa tracking down
the arms dealer. I can't get hold of him.
클라크는 하이파에서 무기상을
추적 중인데 연락이 안돼요
I don't know what to do.
어쩌면 좋죠?
Girl... girlfriend.
자네... 여자 친구
She...
그건...
She works in Baltimore
so... I don't know.
볼티모어에 있었으니까...
모르겠습니다
Spinnaker.
스피나커
- What?
- Spinnaker.
- 네?
- 스피나커
Sir?
국장님?
Bill?
국장님
Yeah. We found the receiver address
for the crate.
그래, 지금 들어왔는데
화물 수취인 주소를 알아냈어
Port of Baltimore.
Can you get to the docks?
볼티모어 항이야
부두로 갈 수 있어?
Find the Transcon warehouse.
The name on the manifest is Mason.
트랜스콘 창고로 가
서류엔 메이슨으로 돼 있어
Sorry, I need this truck.
미안하지만 빌리겠습니다
네메로프 격노, 쿠데타 가능성
미국의 자제 필요
Come on.
제발
답장
캐봇 국장 사망, 난 라이언입니다
1968년 도난 플루토늄
어디로 간 거죠?
송신
Shit.
제기랄
(BLEEPING)
스피나커: 이스라엘
이스라엘에서 훔쳤습니까?
아니, 미국이 훔쳐서
이스라엘에 주었다
Sir, we've come up
with another alternative.
각하, 다른 대안을 마련했습니다
A conventional attack on the airbase
where the carrier attack originated.
항모 공격에 참여한 공군 기지에
재래식 공격을 가하는 겁니다
- It's a measured response.
- Non-nuclear.
- 신중한 대응이 좋을 듯 합니다
- 비핵 무기로요
- Is it strong enough?
- Smart bombs and F-16s.
- 공격 강도는?
- 스마트 탄과 F-16을 동원합니다
Can't afford for them to see us as weak.
우릴 만만하게 보게 해선 안되네
They've got to know we have the guts
to take it to the next level.
더 강도 높은 수단을 취할
배짱이 있음을 보여줘야 돼
I think they'll get that message.
잘 알아들을 겁니다
Hit 'em.
개시하게
Eagle's Nest, this is Eagle One.
We have target acquired. Target is lit.
독수리 둥지, 여긴 독수리 1호
목표물 포착, 조준 완료
To make no response
is to invite a greater attack.
계속 침묵하면
또 건드릴 게 분명합니다
American submarines from Norfolk
and Kings Bay are putting to sea.
노포크와 킹스 만에서
잠수함들이 출항하고 있습니다
They carry Trident D3 missiles.
A first strike weapon.
장착된 트라이던트 D3 미사일로
우리를 선제 공격할 수 있습니다
Fowler is not so insane
as to launch a first strike.
파울러는 그 정도의
미치광이는 아니네
Perhaps he doesn't think
it's the first strike.
선제 공격을 당했다고 보는 거죠
Once their Stealth bombers go up,
we will have no choice.
저들의 스텔스 폭격기가 뜨면
우리도 어쩔 수 없습니다
That will be the sign.
핵 공격 신호니까요
How do we convince him
not to launch his bombers?
그럼 어떻게 하면 출격을
안 하도록 설득할 수 있겠나?
- Maybe we should...
- Bring our missiles to highest alert.
- 제 생각에는...
- 미사일 발사 태세로 들어가시죠
They'd be crazy to attack then.
제정신이라면 공격 못 합니다
Can I have your attention?
잠깐 주목해주세요
The generator has gone out.
발전기가 고장 났어요
There's broken glass everywhere.
Stay where you are. We will get...
깨진 유리가 사방에 널려 있으니
자리에 그대로 계시면 저희가...
OK. Please, stay where you are.
We'll get you one by one.
네, 그대로 계세요
한 사람씩 봐드릴게요
Sir, can you hear me?
Can you feel your arms and legs?
제 말 들리세요?
팔다리에 감각 있어요?
A 9% IV and morphine drip.
Sir, we're gonna take care of you.
9% IV 액에 모르핀 첨가
봐드릴 테니 안심하세요
What have you got?
여긴 어때?
What do we do with the ones
we know won't make it?
가망 없다는 걸 아는데 어쩌라고?
Whatever we can.
끝까지 해봐야지
What?
뭔가?
Bill Cabot died.
캐봇이 사망했답니다
I'm really sorry.
정말 유감입니다
This can't be happening.
어떻게 이런 일이...
Sir, we have a call from Langley.
랭글리에서 전화입니다
Thank you.
알았네
- Becker.
- This is Jack Ryan.
- 베커입니다
- 네, 잭 라이언입니다
Great. The Nemerov apologist.
이런, 네메로프 옹호자시군
Sir, this bomb was not Nemerov.
I know this guy.
네메로프가 한 짓이 아닙니다
제가 잘 압니다
You said that after Grozny.
Put it in your report.
체첸 사태 때도 그러더니
보고서에나 쓰게
The plutonium...
플루토늄은...
Seems unusual to find
radiation poisoning here.
이상하군요, 이런 곳에서
방사능 오염이라뇨
I have never seen such a thing.
이런 일은 처음입니다
That is why we published the case
on the internet-to seek help.
그래서 인터넷에 도움을
요청하는 글을 올린 겁니다
- How did he say it happened?
- He will not talk about it.
- 어쩌다 그렇게 됐답니까?
- 입을 다물고 있습니다
Was anyone else exposed
to the materials that made you sick?
혹시 다른 사람도
그걸 만진 적이 있습니까?
Mr. Ghazi, I'm not the police.
가지 씨, 난 경찰이 아닙니다
I'm a physician. I assure you,
anything you say stays between us.
의사예요, 다 비밀로
해드릴 테니 말씀하세요
My friend and I find bomb.
내 친구와 폭탄을 발견했는데
We sell to a man
who buys such things.
그런 걸 사는 사람에게 팔았어요
Was it this man?
이 사람입니까?
Other people may have come
in contact with that bomb.
다른 사람들도
접촉됐을 지 모릅니다
(ARABIC) We must help them.
그들도 치료해야죠
I am... going to die?
나는... 죽게 되나요?
Yes?
그래요?
Yes.
네
His name is Olson.
그 자의 이름은... 올슨입니다
He live in Damascus.
다마스커스에 살아요
(BLEEPING)
Oh, yeah. We're getting it all.
그래, 모조리 받아보자고
A nuclear strike on Colorado Springs
would take out NORAD.
콜로라도 스프링즈에 핵 공격을
가하면 북미방공사령부가 마비되고
It would limit their ability
to launch a counter-attack.
그럼 반격 능력이
현저히 저하될 겁니다
How many people live
in Colorado Springs?
그곳 주민은 몇 명이나 되나?
Three or four hundred thousand.
30-40만쯤 됩니다
Mr. President, to use nuclear weapons
against the Americans...
대통령 각하, 일단 미국에 대해
핵무기를 사용하게 되면
...would be to cross a threshold.
되돌릴 수 없게 됩니다
They think we already have. Should we
now wait for them to annihilate us?
우리를 의심하고 있네, 우리를
전멸시킬 때까지 기다리란 건가?
I cannot stop what I did not start.
내가 시작한 게 아니니
막을 수가 없군
Mr. President, we need you
to initiate snapcount.
각하, 스냅카운트를
시작해야 합니다
What happens then?
그 후의 과정은?
We prepare to take out their land-based
missiles with a nuclear strike,
대규모 핵 공격으로 적 지상에
배치된 미사일을 제거하고
find and kill their subs, knock out
the planes they have on the ground
해양의 잠수함들을 격침시키고
지상의 항공기들을 파괴하며
and mobilise our fighters to destroy
the ones they already have in the air.
공중에 있는 적기는
전투기로 제거하게 됩니다
What are our chances?
성공 가능성은?
David?
데이비드?
Odds are we leave Nemerov
in a pretty pickle.
예측컨대... 네메로프는
곤경에 처할 겁니다
He'll be left with, at best,
a few hundred nukes,
기껏해야 우리가
미처 찾아내지 못한
the ones we can't find.
수백 개의 폭탄만 남죠
Mostly the... smaller, more mobile,
less accurate kind.
대부분은 소형에 운반은 쉽지만
정확도는 떨어집니다
All those can do is target our cities.
도시만을 목표로 삼을 수 있죠
But he knows to an absolute certainty
that we will respond against his cities.
하지만 우리도 그 쪽 도시들에
반격을 가하리란 걸 알 겁니다
I spent my entire adult life
wanting to be President.
난 대통령이 되기 위해
반평생을 바쳤네
This is my presidency?
그런데 이게 뭔가?
Sir, I think he'll keep his 300 nukes as a
deterrent against any future aggressor.
다른 적국으로부터의 공격 억지용
폭탄 3백여 개는 보유할 것이므로
I think he'll push back from the table
and call it a night.
결국 그 쪽에서 먼저
손을 들고 말 겁니다
I'm giving the order for snapcount.
Maximum readiness.
스냅카운트를 시작하게
최고 수준으로
Olson had wire payments of $45 million
from someone named Dressler.
잭, 드레슬러란 자로부터 올슨에게
4천 5백만 불이 송금됐어
Find out who Dressler is.
Jack, I want you out of there.
딜론, 드레슬러에 대해 알아봐
잭, 어서 거기서 나와
- I'm at the docks.
- Look for the name Dressler.
- 벌써 부두에 도착했어요
- 드레슬러란 자를 찾아
No! Jack, get out.
Dillon, give Baltimore PD the address.
아냐, 잭, 나와, 딜론, 경찰에
전화해서 부두로 출동하라고 해
- Wait for the cops.
- I'll call you back.
- 경찰이 갈 거야
- 다시 걸게요
Who's Dressler?
드레슬러가 누구야?
Where is he, goddamn it?
그 놈 어디 있어?
Where is Dressler?
드레슬러 어디 있어?
Police! Put your hands up!
경찰이다, 손 들어
- Where's Dressler?
- Are you Jack Ryan?
- 드레슬러 어디 있어? 어서 말해
- 당신이 잭 라이언입니까?
- Where's Dressler, goddamn it?
- Let him go!
- 어디 있는지 말해, 어서
- 됐어요, 놔요
Where's Dressler? Where is he?
어서 말해, 어디 있어?
Langley said you might need help.
도와주라고 해서 왔어요
- I gotta get to the Pentagon.
- I can help you.
- 국방부에 가야 돼요
- 그건 도와줄 수 있어요
Mr. President.
대통령 각하
Their Stealth bombers
have left Aviano.
스텔스 폭격 편대가
아비아노를 떠났습니다
That is the sign.
핵 공격입니다
Shoot them down.
영공에 들어오면 격추시키게
God protect us.
신의 가호를...
Mr. President, they're scrambling
their fighters. We're out of time.
각하, 요격기들이 출격한답니다
시간이 없습니다
- Dave!
- He has a heart condition.
- 데이브
- 심장 질환이 있어요
- Get a doctor.
- Mr. President.
- 의사 부르게
- 각하
- Where's your nitro?
- I said get a doctor!
- 비상 약 어디 있나?
- 의사 부르라니까
- Mr. President.
- Take him to my quarters.
- 각하
- 내 침실로 옮기게
Colonel, bring in the launch codes.
대령, 발사 암호 가져와
Dressler's an Austrian manufacturer,
billionaire.
드레슬러는 오스트리아의
억만장자 기업가야
His father was executed at Nuremberg.
아버진 뉘른베르크에서 처형됐지
He bought a seat in parliament and got
booted out for saying pro-Nazi things.
돈으로 의회에 진출했다가
친 나치적 발언을 일삼아 축출됐어
Rudy, get me through to the President.
루디, 대통령께 연결해줘
I can't do it, Jack.
They're in the snapcount.
지금은 안돼, 잭
스냅카운트에 들어가서
- There's no way in.
- Bullshit.
- 외부와 차단됐어
- 제기랄
- I can do that for you, sir.
- No, it's fine. Got some dirt on it.
- 제가 해드리죠
- 됐어요, 카드에 흙이 묻어서
- Can I see it? We're on high alert.
- I understand.
- 경계령이 내려져 확인해야 해요
- 그렇겠죠
- Sir, put the card down.
- Back off.
- 카드를 내려 놓으시죠
- 가만 있어요
- I am ordering you...
- Back off!
- 이건 명령입니다
- 가만 있으라니까
Step back now! I am ordering
you to take a step back! Put...
뒤로 물러서요, 어서 물러서요
그렇지 않으면...
General, there's a Dr. Ryan
from the CIA.
장군님, CIA의 라이언 박사가
He wants to enter NMCC.
He's unescorted.
전군사령부에 들어가길
원하는데 혼자입니다
- What's he want?
- You, sir.
- 뭘 원하는데?
- 장군님입니다
I have a message from Director Cabot
that I need to transmit over the hotline.
장군님, 캐봇 국장님이 핫라인으로
전하라는 긴급 메시지가 있어서요
- What's your authorisation?
- I don't have one.
- 위임장은 어디 있나?
- 그런 거 없습니다
- Where's Cabot?
- Cabot's dead, sir.
- 그럼 국장님은?
- 사망하셨습니다
- I need to get this information sent.
- Not without authorisation. Get him out.
- 급히 보내야 합니다
- 위임장 없인 안되네, 내보내
Wait! General! The President is basing
his decisions on bad information!
장군님, 대통령께서는 잘못된
정보에 의거해 판단을 내리십니다
If you shut me out,
your family and my family
절 쫓아내면 장군님의
가족과 제 가족
and 25 million other families
will be dead in 30 minutes!
2천 5백만 명의 다른 사람들이
30분 후에 다 죽습니다
My orders are to get this information
to the people who make the decisions.
전 최고 결정권자들에게
올바른 정보를 알려줘야 합니다
I just need to send some information.
이걸 보내기만 하면 됩니다
What makes you think
the President will listen to you?
대통령께서 귀를 기울이겠나?
He doesn't have to.
그분이 아닙니다
How close are the bombers?
전폭기들의 현재 위치는?
They're slipping in and out of radar
over Poland.
폴란드 상공에서 간헐적으로
레이다에 잡히고 있습니다
Activate the missile regiments.
미사일 연대에 발사 준비를 시키게
The launch takes a minute to process
after you give the order.
명령을 내린 후 1분 간의
발사 준비 시간이 소요됩니다
Before the order can be taken,
an ID check must be performed.
명령 수행 전
그 확인 절차가 필요합니다
Mine is the... My number is...
내 번호... 내 번호는...
the third... third number down
from the top.
위로부터... 세 번째에 있는 거네
Your order, sir?
명령을 내리십시오
- Strike.
- I'm sorry, sir?
- 공격하게
- 뭐라고 하셨죠?
I give the order to strike.
공격하라고 했네
Under the two-man rule, the order
to strike must now be confirmed.
2인 승인 규칙에 따라
공격 명령을 확인합니다
Bob, for the love of God.
하느님을 위해서 제발...
Just do it.
어서 하게
Sidney Owens, Secretary of State.
It's the fourth number down.
국무장관 시드니 오웬스
위에서 네 번째 번호
The order to strike has now been
confirmed by the two-man rule.
공격 명령은 2인 승인 규칙에 따라
확인됐습니다
NMCC, strike order has been
confirmed. Start the sequence.
전군사령부, 공격 명령이 승인됐다
절차를 시작하라
- We've activity on the hotline.
- They had their chance.
- 핫라인이 작동합니다
- 이미 끝난 일이야
No, somebody's talking to the Kremlin.
누군가 크레믈린과
얘기하고 있습니다
It says, "America has been the victim
of a terrorist attack."
미국은 테러 공격의
희생자가 됐답니다
As you can imagine, there has
been much confusion here...
잘 알겠지만
여긴 혼란과 두려움에...
...and fear.
빠져 있습니다
But we know the weapon
was not Russian.
하지만 러시아의
폭탄이 아니란 걸 압니다
"But we know the weapon
was not Russian."
'하지만 러시아의 폭탄이
아니란 걸 압니다', 다시 반복
What's going on?
뭘 하자는 거지?
Type exactly what I say.
그대로 보내
Who are we talking to?
당신은 누구시오?
Ryan. I met you in Moscow with
Bill Cabot. He died today in Baltimore.
라이언입니다, 모스크바에서
국장님과 뵈었죠, 오늘 죽었습니다
- Cut him off.
- Launch sequence has begun.
- 차단시켜
- 발사 절차에 들어갔습니다
Two months ago, a neo-fascist
named Dressler bought an A-bomb.
두 달 전
드레슬러란 신파시스트가
암시장에서 원폭을 구입했습니다
- Cut him off.
- The system can't be cut off.
- 차단하라니까
- 현재로선 차단이 불가능합니다
Then get someone to stop him.
그럼 누가 내려가서 막아
- He paid three disaffected Russian...
- "scientists to make the bomb active.
- 러시아 과학자 셋을 매수해...
- '...폭탄을 복원시켰습니다'
"He shipped it to the US,
where a man named Mason"
'그걸 미국에 보내
메이슨이란 자로 하여금'
was hired to deliver the bomb and
set our countries on a collision course.
폭탄을 터뜨려 우리 두 나라를
전쟁으로 몰아넣으려 했습니다
This is madness. He is CIA.
다 속임수입니다
CIA는 못 믿습니다
We cannot hang our fate
on the word of their spy.
스파이의 말에
우리 운명을 맡길 수는 없죠
What is the harm of listening
a bit more?
좀더 들어보심이 어떨지...
What are you asking of me?
내게 뭘 바라는 건가?
Back down.
물러나십시오
What guarantee do I have that
President Fowler will follow suit?
파울러 대통령도 나처럼
하리라고 장담할 수 있겠나?
None.
없습니다
You see? He is wasting time.
보십시오
시간을 끌려는 수작입니다
We must launch now.
We have only moments.
지금 발사하지 않으면 늦습니다
Sir, I know you had nothing to do
with the Baltimore bomb
미국에서 터진 핵 폭탄과는
아무 관련이 없음을 압니다
and you know you didn't, but you're
still about to launch a nuclear strike.
본인이 그걸 잘 아시면서도
지금 핵 공격을 하려 하십니다
- Yes, sir. That's all, Dr. Ryan.
- This is about fear.
- 알겠습니다, 그만 하게, 라이언
- 다 두려움 때문이죠
Fear of your missiles,
fear of our subs.
상대의 미사일과
잠수함에 대한 두려움이자
Fear of being weak,
of making a mistake,
상대의 불신에 대한 두려움이고
the fear of the other guy that had us
build these bombs in the first place!
핵 경쟁을 야기시킨
상대에 대한 두려움입니다!
It's stopped.
끊어졌습니다
They cut him off.
차단시켰습니다
They are going to strike.
공격을 개시할 겁니다
Prepare the launch orders now.
어서 발사 태세를 갖춰
30 seconds to launch.
발사 30초 전
Oh, my God. Mr. President?
오, 하느님, 대통령 각하?
내 명령에 의거
러시아 군의 경계령을 해제합니다
We will maintain our defensive alert
for the moment,
방공망은 현 상태로 유지할 테지만
but our offensive forces
are withdrawn.
공격 태세는 해제되고 있습니다
"If you match this, I propose a phased
mutual stand down over five hours."
'5시간에 걸친 공격 태세에 대한
단계적 상호 해제를 제안합니다'
Stop the launch sequence.
발사 절차 중지하게
Lasseter here. Flash override.
Stop the sequence!
라세터 장군이다, 긴급 중지
당장 중지시켜, 당장
Order the planes to stand down.
Take us to DEFCON-3.
전폭기들 불러 들이고
데프콘-3로 내리게
And would somebody ask Mr. Ryan
if I can use the phone now?
전화를 써도 되는지
그 친구한테 물어봐 주게
You're still here.
아직 안 갔네
(OPERA: "NESSUN DORMA"
BY PUCCINI)
미 합중국을 대표하여
("NESSUN DORMA" CONTINUES)
러시아 연방을 대표하여
(APPLAUSE)
There is no more fitting memorial
for those who perished in this tragedy
이번 주에 우리가 취한 조치는
이번 비극의 희생자들에게
than the steps we've taken this week
최고의 추도식이 될 것입니다
toward a multinational campaign
다른 나라들의 동참으로
to root out and eliminate
weapons of mass destruction.
대량 살상 무기를
제거할 발판을 마련했습니다
We embarked on this course because
we have learned, at too great a cost,
우린 너무나 큰 대가를 치르고
오늘의 소중한 교훈을 얻었습니다
that if the most powerful weapons
ever created are unleashed,
이 지구상에 가공할
무기들이 쓰이는 건
they will be fired not in anger,
but in fear.
분노가 아닌 두려움에서
비롯됨을 깨달았습니다
Dr. Ryan.
라이언 박사
Mr. Grushkov.
그루쉬코프 씨
It is... a lovely day.
아주 멋진 날입니다
Yeah.
네
- I'm sorry, this is...
- Dr. Muller. How do you do?
- 죄송합니다, 이쪽은...
- 멀러 박사, 안녕하십니까?
Nice to meet you.
안녕하세요
Why am I not surprised
that you know her name?
어떻게 이름을
아는지 놀랍진 않네요
Our friend William
thought I was a spy.
내 친구 캐봇은 날 스파이로 봤소
Of course, he could never prove it.
물론 입증할 수는 없었지만
He never told me you were friends.
친구 사이인 줄은 몰랐는데요
Maybe he didn't know you well enough.
더 친해졌으면 말했을 거요
He told me he had a source in Russia.
러시아에 '출처'가 있다고 했죠
"To keep the back channels open?"
'뒤쪽에 대화 채널을 열어 놨다?'
"In hopes of staving off disaster."
'재난을 방지하기 위해서요'
Kennedy said,
"Our most basic common link
케네디 대통령은 말했습니다
'우리를 이어주는 것은'
"is that we all inhabit
this small planet.
'우리 모두 이 작은
행성에 사는 주민들로서'
"We all breathe the same air.
'같은 공기를 호흡하고'
"We all cherish our children's future...
'어린이들의 미래를
소중히 여기며'
"...and we are all mortal."
'결국엔 죽는다는 사실이다'
I will miss... so very much
talking to William.
캐봇과의 대화가...
그리워지게 될 거요
Me, too.
저도요
Perhaps from time to time
그럼... 앞으로 종종...
you and I can talk.
대화를 합시다
Yeah, I'd like that.
네, 좋습니다
What is this?
뭘 주시는 거죠?
A modest gift for your engagement.
조촐한 약혼 축하 선물이오
He just asked me this morning.
오늘 아침에 청혼 했는데...
We haven't told anybody about it.
아무한테도 말 안 했는데...
How could you possibly know?
대체 어떻게 안 거죠?
♪ Remember
♪ If we could remember
♪ The moment of our birth
♪ We'd give our voice
To songs and whispers
♪ And know what life is worth
♪ Remember
♪ Suddenly there's beauty
♪ In pieces of the past
♪ And sorrow clings
♪ To angry questions
♪ The days of dust at last
♪ And morning holds out
♪ When worlds come tumbling down
♪ A dance of ghosts
spin around your dreams
♪ Spinning round
♪ I remember
♪ Remember
♪ Remember, remember
♪ If we could remember
♪ The power of the light
♪ That crippled prayers
are sometimes answered
♪ And hope survives the night
♪ And hope
♪ Survives
♪ The night
♪ I remember
♪ I remember, remember
♪ Remember
♪ Remember ♪